The Huntington Library
Arthur M. Ellis Collection of Photographic Negatives
1849-1923
bulk 1880s-1890s
The Huntington Library 1151 Oxford Road San Marino, CA 91108 Phone: 626-405-2180 Email: jwatts@huntington.org
Ellis, Arthur M. (Arthur McDonald), 1875-1932.
28 linear feet, 67 boxes
The collection consists of 1366 photographic prints (mostly copy prints from 8 x 10 inch glass plate and film negatives), 1520 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives, glass positives, film negatives and lantern slides, 203 8 x 10 inch glass plate negatives, and 734 8 x10 inch film negatives depicting Southern California (mainly Los Angeles and nearby communities) and spanning the years ca. 1850 to the 1920s. The collection provides quite a comprehensive picture of the growth and development of Los Angeles at the turn of the twentieth century.
photCL 188
Biographical Note
Arthur McDonald Ellis (1875-1932) was born in Missouri. When he was two years old, his parents moved the family to California, where his grandfather had settled in the early 1850s. Ellis was educated in Pomona and at the University of California, Berkeley. Upon graduation he began a teaching career, but left the profession after a few years to study law. He established his practice in Los Angeles in 1903.
Ellis studied history while at Berkeley, and his interest in the subject was life-long. He served as director of the Historical Society of Southern California, and was its president during 1927-1928. He was also a trustee of the Southwest Museum. He lectured statewide on California history and accumulated a large collection of photographs and slides depicting Southern California and the Southwest which he used in his presentations. He published a number of books, including The Indians of Los Angeles County (1926), a collection of letters of early pioneer Hugo Reid that provided firsthand accounts of the Native Americans of California and their treatment by the Mission padres.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 1366 photographic prints (mostly copy prints from 8 x 10 inch glass plate and film negatives), 1520 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives, glass positives, film negatives and lantern slides, 203 8 x 10 inch glass plate negatives, and 734 8 x10 inch film negatives depicting Southern California (mainly Los Angeles and nearby communities) and spanning the years ca. 1850 to the 1920s. The collection provides quite a comprehensive picture of the growth and development of Los Angeles at the turn of the twentieth century. There are no prints or other viewing surrogates for the smaller format glass negatives and lantern slides; viewing must be arranged through the Curator of Photographs. These smaller format items are mostly copy negatives (not originals) taken by Ellis of images in other collections, apparently for reference purposes or to document already existing collections. Ellis copied the photographic holdings of, among others, Bancroft, Behrendt, Tyler, Hill, Ingersoll, Forman, Rowan, Foxley, Guinn, Fryer, A.W. Francisco, McPherson, Charles Prudhomme and William Burton.
The collection is particularly strong in images of central Los Angeles from the 1880s to the 1910s and Los Angeles County beach communities in the 1900s and 1910s. Also of note are images of sites and themes of historic or cultural significance, and portraits. In addition to images of central Los Angeles, the collection includes images of Los Angeles County beach communities; Pasadena and the San Gabriel Valley; and Orange, Ventura, San Bernardino and San Diego Counties. The historic and cultural sites include photographs of missions and churches; commercial, municipal and residential buildings, including historic adobes; schools and parks; railroads, emigration, and stagecoach routes; Campo de Cahuenga; Busch Gardens in Pasadena; the Modjeska home in Santa Ana; the Lake Vineyard, Sunnyslope, and the Rowland properties in the San Gabriel Valley; and images of Native Americans and Native American culture. Portraits include those of California pioneers, prominent Angelenos and San Diegans, including J. Lancaster Brent, George Horatio Derby, Hillard Dorsey, the Ellis Family, Judge A.J. King and family, Vicente Lugo, Charles Prudhomme, Truman H. Rose, William Rubottom, Abel Stearns, 1st Worshipful Master of the California Masonic Lodge Levi Stowall, and the Workman family.
Some of the 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives and lantern slides depict historic sites of Northern California, including mining camps of the California Gold Rush. There are also miscellaneous images pertaining to themes with no direct relationship to California or the American West. These images depict a number of unrelated themes including Freemasonry (a few documents, images depicting early Californian Masonic Temples and the Alexandria Temple in Virginia) and general United States history. The United States history images include copies of Abraham Lincoln portraits and the Lincoln home in Kentucky as well as early American figures including George Washington and Benjamin Franklin.
Many of the 8 x 10 inch glass negatives are by Graham Photo Company. There are also a number of photographs by William H. Fletcher. Among the 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives are a significant number of images by William H. Godfrey depicting central Los Angeles and the San Gabriel Valley. There are also photographs by F.H. Rogers, Parker, W.A. Vale and Carleton Watkins in addition to photographs of a number of Edward Vischer illustrations. Ellis also took photographs of land surveys by George Hansen, Edward Otho Cresap Ord and Frank Lecouvreur.
Many of the copy prints exist in duplicate and all prints are annotated with location information and description on the reverse, when known. Some of the 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives and lantern slides depict the same image two or more times, but as they appeared in the albums or collections of different individuals. Details and enlargements are also present. Description and location information are noted on the envelope of the negatives when known.
Arrangement
Boxes 1-10 contain copy and original photographs; they have been described at the folder level. Every effort has been made to be as inclusive as possible in the description of the folder contents; some folders labeled Miscellaneous, span multiple subjects without any apparent relationship to one another.
Boxes 11-47 contain 4 x 5 inch and smaller glass negatives, glass positives, film negatives and lantern slides. There are no prints or other viewing surrogates for this portion of the collection. Viewing must be arranged through the Curator of Photographs. These images have been organized by geographic region where possible, starting with Central Los Angeles and Los Angeles County and moving out into the surrounding California counties. Locations and subjects not related to California history follow. Miscellaneous and unidentified images, photographs by William M. Godfrey, and a very small number of 5 x 7 inch glass negatives are at the end of the collection.
Boxes 48-67 contain 8 x 10 inch glass plate and film negatives corresponding to the collection's black and white prints.
The collection has also been intellectually described by geographic region and subject matter. This arrangement follows the Container List. The geographical list is arranged by proximity to central Los Angeles. The Subject list is arranged alphabetically.
Indexing Terms
Personal Names
Brent, Joseph Lancaster, 1826-1905.; Derby, George Horatio, 1823-1861.; Dorsey, Hillard.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790.; King, A. J., Judge.; Lincoln, Abraham 1809-1865.; Lugo, Vicente.; Prudhomme, Charles J., 1854-1934.; Rose, Truman H.; Rowland, John, 1791-1873.; Rubottom, William.; Stearns, Abel, 1798-1871.; Stowall, Levi.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Wilson, Benjamin Davis, 1811-1878.; Workman family.
Subjects
Amusement parks California Los Angeles County Photographs.; Beaches California Los Angeles County Photographs.; Cityscapes California Los Angeles Photographs.; Church buildings California Los Angeles Photographs.; Commercial buildings California Los Angeles Photographs.; Dwellings California Los Angeles Photographs.; Farms California San Gabriel Valley Photographs.; Freemasonry Photographs.; Gold mines and mining California Photographs.; Historic buildings California Photographs.; Indians of North America Portraits.; Missions California Photographs.; Municipal buildings California Photographs.; Orchards California San Gabriel Valley Photographs.; Parks California Los Angeles Photographs.; Railroads Trains Photographs.; Ranches California San Gabriel Valley Photographs.; Schools California Photographs.; Seaside resorts California Los Angeles County Photographs.; Stagecoaches Photographs.; United States History 18th century Photographs.; United States History 19th century Photographs.; Vineyards California San Gabriel Valley Photographs.; Wagon trains Photographs.
Places
Busch Gardens (Pasadena, Calif.) Photographs.; Campo de Cahuenga (Universal City, Calif.) Photographs.; Los Angeles County (Calif.) Photographs.; Lincoln Homestead State Park, Kentucky Photographs.; Modjeska Ranch (Calif.) Photographs.; Orange County (Calif.) Photographs.; Pasadena (Calif.) Photographs.; San Bernardino County (Calif.) Photographs.; San Diego County (Calif.) Photographs.; San Gabriel Valley (Calif.) Photographs.; Sunny Slope Ranch (Calif.) Photographs.; Ventura County (Calif.) Photographs.
Genres and Forms of Material
Photographs.
Contributors
Fletcher, W. H. (William H.).; Godfrey, W. M. (William Mollock), 1825-1900.; Vale, W. A., b. 1847.; Watkins, Carleton E., 1829-1916.; Vischer, Edward.; Hansen, George, 1824-1897.; Ord, Edward Otho Cresap, 1818-1883.; Lecouvreur, Frank, 1829-1901.; Graham Photo Co.; F.H. Rogers Co.
Restrictions on Access
Access is granted to qualified researchers and by appointment.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Huntington Library by Mrs. Arthur (Bessie) Ellis, 1945, 1946, 1950.
Physical Characteristics or Technical Requirements
No viewing surrogates are available for the collection's glass plate negatives and positives, lantern slides, and film negatives located in boxes 11-47. Arrangements for viewing these items must be made with the Curator of Photographs.
- Container List
  - Orange County. Arch Beach, Laguna Beach, ca. 1915; undated (Box 1, Item 1-34)
  - Madame Modjeskas home, Orange County; San Diego; Riverside; Missions, 1901-1902; undated (Box 1, Item 40-59)
  - Missions. San Gabriel Arcangel; San Juan Capistrano, undated (Box 1, Item 60-82)
  - Missions. San Fernando Rey; San Buenaventura; Santa Barbara; Santa Ynez; La Purisima Concepcion; Santa Clara, undated; [Nos. 101, 108 missing as of December 2005.] (Box 1, Item 83-108)
  - Pasadena, 1887-1904; undated (Box 1, Item 109-129)
  - Pasadena. Busch Gardens, 1909-1914; undated; [Includes Graham Photo Co. photographs.] (Box 1, Item 130-150)
  - Pasadena. Busch Gardens; Busch Residence, 1914; undated; [Includes Graham Photo Co. photographs.] (Box 2, Item 151-170)
  - Pasadena. Busch Gardens; fairy tale scenes, ca. 1910; undated; [Includes Graham Photo Co. photographs.] (Box 2, Item 171-182)
  - San Gabriel Valley. Baldwins Ranch; Arcadia; San Gabriel; Monrovia; Duarte; Pomona, ca. 1890; undated; [Includes photographs taken by William H. Fletcher.] (Box 2, Item 183-197)
  - San Pedro, 1897-1921; undated; [Includes photographs taken by William H. Fletcher.] (Box 2, Item 198-231)
  - Long Beach, ca. 1910-1915; undated (Box 2, Item 232-250)
  - Santa Catalina Island; Redondo Beach, ca. 1898-1910 (Box 2, Item 251-267)
  - Venice, ca. 1915; undated (Box 3, Item 268-286)
  - Santa Monica, ca. 1910; undated (Box 3, Item 287-304)
  - Los Angeles County. Cahuenga Valley; Echo Park area, ca. 1886-1897; undated; [Includes photographs taken by William H. Fletcher.] (Box 3, Item 305-317B)
  - Central Los Angeles street views, 1854; 1887-1898,; undated; [Includes photographs taken by William H. Fletcher.] (Box 3, Item 318-341)
  - Central Los Angeles streets and residences; Central Park, 1885-1912; undated; [Includes photographs taken by William H. Fletcher.] (Box 3, Item 353-365)
  - Central Los Angeles street scenes, 1902-1918; undated (Box 3, Item 366-395)
  - Central Los Angeles. Municipal buildings; Commercial buildings; Churches, ca. 1915; undated (Box 4, Item 396-428)
  - Southwest scenery; Los Angeles transportation, 1912; 1915,; undated (Box 4, Item 429-448)
  - Central Los Angeles residences; Plaza area, 1861-1885; undated (Box 4, Item 449-477)
  - Los Angeles Plaza area, 1857-1895; undated (Box 4, Item 478-501)
  - Central Los Angeles. Birds-eye views; Buildings, 1856-1894; undated (Box 4, Item 502-521)
  - Central Los Angeles. Schools and clubs; Parades; Parks, 1871-1899; undated (Box 4, Item 522-546)
  - Central Los Angeles street scenes, 1860-1921; undated (Box 5, Item 547-576)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes; Birds-eye views, 1857-1900; undated (Box 5, Item 577-606)
  - Railroads; Santa Monica, 1869-1923; undated (Box 5, Item 607-635)
  - Ocean Park; Venice, 1920-1923; undated (Box 5, Item 636-662)
  - Venice; Hermosa Beach, ca. 1920; undated (Box 6, Item 663-682)
  - Redondo; San Pedro, 1894-1920; undated (Box 6, Item 683-709)
  - San Pedro; Wilmington, 1850s; 1912-1917,; undated (Box 6, Item 710-729)
  - Long Beach; Cerritos Ranch, 1870s-1918; undated; [No. 749 missing as of December 2005.] (Box 6, Item 730-757)
  - Santa Catalina Island; Huntington Beach; Newport Beach; Balboa Beach, ca. 1915-1920; undated (Box 6, Item 758-782)
  - San Diego County; Imperial Valley, 1880s; 1894,; undated (Box 6, Item 786-799)
  - Missions; Adobes, 1890-1931; undated (Box 6, Item 800-826)
  - Firestone Tire Rubber; Oil fields, 1907; 1919-1928 (Box 7, Item 827-851)
  - Los Angeles churches, 1870; 1895,; 1915,; 1920s,; undated (Box 7, Item 852-873)
  - Los Angeles County parks, 1880-1894; 1920s,; undated (Box 7, Item 874-892)
  - Schools; Campo de Cahuenga; Cahuenga Valley, 1877; 1896-1899,; undated; [Includes narratives by Otto Weid.] (Box 7, Item 893-908)
  - Hollywood, 1894-1903; 1920s,; 1930s,; undated (Box 7, Item 909-932)
  - San Fernando; San Gabriel; Eagle Rock; Pasadena; Los Angeles hotels, 1884-1919; undated (Box 7, Item 933-953)
  - Central Los Angeles buildings, 1889-1925; undated (Box 8, Item 954-977)
  - Central Los Angeles street scenes; Construction progress on Los Angeles Railway building, 1890-1920; undated (Box 8, Item 978-1006)
  - Central Los Angeles street scenes and buildings, 1906-1923; undated (Box 8, Item 1007-1036C)
  - Central Los Angeles street scenes, 1905-1922; undated (Box 8, Item 1037-1057)
  - Beach cities; Miscellaneous beaches, 1894; 1923,; undated (Box 8, Item 1058-1076)
  - Central Los Angeles and vicinity. Street scenes; Residences, 1919; undated (Box 8, Item 1077-1096)
  - Camulos Rancho; Santa Cruz; Ventura County; Automobile related photographs in Los Angeles, 1860; 1894-1920, undated; undated (Box 9, Item 1097-1123)
  - Portraits, 1849-1900; undated (Box 9, Item 1124-1151)
  - Monuments; Historic landmarks, undated (Box 9, Item 1152-1179)
  - Indian village and exhibit, Eastlake Park, Los Angeles, ca. 1907 (Box 10, Item 1180-1185)
  - Unidentified Native Americans, undated (Box 10, Item 1186-1189)
  - Central Los Angeles buildings and street scenes, 1923; undated; [No. 1216 missing as of December 2005.] (Box 10, Item 1190-1226)
  - Central Los Angeles buildings and street scenes, 1923; undated (Box 10, Item 1227-1241)
  - Los Angeles County. Gardens; Parks; Residential streets, undated (Box 10, Item 1243-1251)
  - Miscellaneous scenery, undated (Box 10, Item 1252-1257)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Item 1258-1263)
  - Boxes 11-58 house glass plates. Viewing must be arranged with Curator of Photographs.
  - Drawings of Los Angeles, 1850s (Box 11, Item 1264-1265a)
  - Los Angeles. Plaza; Pico House; Plaza Church, 1857; 1891,; undated (Box 11, Item 1266-1291)
  - Los Angeles. Avila Adobe/Stocktons Headquarters, undated (Box 11, Item 1292-1295)
  - Los Angeles. Sonoratown, 1875-1885; undated (Box 11, Item 1296-1299)
  - Los Angeles. Sonoratown; Chinatown; Negro Alley, 1880; undated (Box 12, Item 1300-1308)
  - Los Angeles. Businesses and street scenes along Los Angeles, 1st, Temple and Commercial Streets, 1862-1872; undated (Box 12, Item 1309-1315a)
  - Los Angeles. Abel Stearns residence, El Palacio, 1850; undated (Box 12, Item 1316-1320)
  - Los Angeles. North Main Street, 1868-1885; undated (Box 12, Item 1321-1336)
  - Los Angeles. North Main Street; Temple Block and vicinity, 1862; undated (Box 13, Item 1337-1345)
  - Los Angeles. Temple Block, 1876; undated (Box 13, Item 1346-1351)
  - Los Angeles. Old Court House, 1868; 1875,; undated (Box 13, Item 1352-1356)
  - Los Angeles. Old Court House; Bella Union/St. Charles Hotel, photos and litho, 1858-1880; undated (Box 14, Item 1357-1365)
  - Los Angeles. Main Street between 1st and 3rd. Workmans store; Meyers residence; St. Vibianas Cathedral and views from St. Vibianas, 1870-1889; undated (Box 14, Item 1366-1379)
  - Los Angeles. Main Street between 3rd and 6th including Street views and buildings; Pacific Electric Building, 1883; 1900,; 1918,; undated (Box 14, Item 1380-1386)
  - Los Angeles. Pacific Electric Building (continued); Residences on Main St. (exact locations unknown), undated (Box 14, Item 1387-1390)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes and buildings along 2nd Street; Views from 2nd Street, 1870; undated (Box 15, Item 1391-1395)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes and buildings along Spring Street to 3rd Street including the Nadeau Block and Phillips Block; Views of the Wolfskill Ranch from Spring Street and 3rd Street, 1889; 1892,; 1912,; undated (Box 15, Item 1396-1412)
  - Los Angeles. Wolfskill Ranch orchards and fruit trees, undated (Box 15, Item 1413-1415)
  - Los Angeles. Round House and Garden of Paradise, undated (Box 15, Item 1416-1421)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes and buildings along S. Spring Street from about 4th Street including Ralphs store, 1903; undated (Box 15, Item 1422-1426)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes; Homes and buildings along S. Spring Street, 1875; 1889,; undated (Box 16, Item 1427-1430)
  - Los Angeles. Homes and buildings along San Pedro Street including the Lugo adobe, 1921; undated (Box 16, Item 1431-1436)
  - Los Angeles. Palm Drive; Agricultural Park; Shrine Auditorium; Chester Place, 1895; undated (Box 16, Item 1437-1440)
  - Los Angeles. Street scenes and homes on Bunker Hill and West Temple Street, including Exposition Hall, 1881; 1883,; undated (Box 16, Item 1441-1447)
  - Los Angeles. Old High School on Pound Cake Hill and views from Pound Cake Hill, 1870-1885; undated (Box 16, Item 1448-1465)
  - Los Angeles. Views from Pound Cake Hill; Red Sandstone Courthouse; St. Athenasius Church, 1891; 1895,; undated (Box 17, Item 1466-1475)
  - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along Fort Street/Broadway to about 5th including Fort St. Methodist Church, old City Hall, Potomac Block, 1871; 1883-1890,; 1902-1913,; undated (Box 17, Item 1476-1506)
  - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along S. Broadway from about 5th Street including Presbyterian Church, Synagogue and St. Vincents School, 1870; 1880,; 1918,; undated (Box 18, Item 1507-1517)
  - Los Angeles. Birds eye views from Fort Hill; Buildings and street scenes along Hill Street, 1870; 1875,; 1910,; undated (Box 18, Item 1518-1538)
  - West Central Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along 4th Street and Olive Streets, 1918; undated (Box 18, Item 1539-1546)
  - West Central Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes including the State Normal School, Hazards Pavilion, Bellevue Terrace Hotel, 1886; ca. 1900,; undated (Box 19, Item 1547-1555)
  - Los Angeles. Central Park and vicinity, 1881; 1885,; undated (Box 19, Item 1556-1562)
  - Los Angeles. Childs property, 1913; undated (Box 19, Item 1563-1565)
  - West Central Los Angeles. Various scenes including streets. Buildings; Westlake Park and the Francisco farm, 1881-1890; undated (Box 19, Item 1566-1579)
  - Los Angeles. Farms and homes on future site of the Southern Branch of the University of California, undated (Box 19, Item 1580-1584)
  - Campo De Cahuenga, undated (Box 19, Item 1585)
  - North East and South East Central Los Angeles including Aliso Street; the Sainsevains property; Beaudry Reservoir; Boyle Heights, 1875; undated (Box 20, Item 1586-1600)
  - Los Angeles. Parades and celebrations including 4th of July, 1871 and 1894 Fiesta, 1876; undated (Box 20, Item 1601-1607)
  - Los Angeles. Hanging of Lachenais, 1871 (Box 20, Item 1608-1609a)
  - Los Angeles. Floods, 1883; undated (Box 20, Item 1610-1613)
  - Arroyo Seco, Pasadena and Glendale including views of the Raymond Hotel and the Ostrich Farm, 1872; undated (Box 20, Item 1614-1621a)
  - Pasadena, San Marino and Sierra Madre including the Lake Vineyard, Sunnyslope, El Molino Viejo and various street scenes, orchards and vineyards, 1871; 1885,; 1921,; undated (Box 21, Item 1622-1652)
  - Various San Gabriel Valley scenes, including Santa Anita Ranch, 1872; undated (Box 21, Item 1653-1662)
  - Rowland Property, 1921; undated (Box 21, Item 1663-1665)
  - El Monte region, including Savannah and Ellis Family Property, 1908-1920; undated (Box 22, Item 1666-1678a)
  - Pomona buildings, street scenes and open land, includes Palomares Hotel and fire, 1880-1890; 1911,; undated (Box 22, Item 1679-1694)
  - Spadra homes and ranches, including the Rubottom home and hotel, undated (Box 22, Item 1695-1699)
  - Spadra (continued), includes "Monkey Town" newspaper clipping, 1885; 1919,; undated (Box 23, Item 1700-1702)
  - Whittier and vicinity including Los Nietos; Pico Ranchita; Rio Hondo Battlefields and San Gabriel River, 1869; 1920-1921,; undated (Box 23, Item 1703-1711)
  - San Pedro and San Pedro Harbor, 1872; 1885,; undated (Box 23, Item 1712-1717)
  - Wilmington, including views of the town; Wilmington Exchange; Wilmington Barracks; Banning House, 1873; 1885,; 1918,; 1923,; undated (Box 23, Item 1718-1726)
  - Santa Monica including Santa Monica Beach and Canyon; Street scenes; Santa Monica Hotel; Engravings, 1872; 1878,; undated (Box 23, Item 1727-1741)
  - Santa Monica (continued). Long Wharf; Sunset Park, undated (Box 24, Item 1742-1743)
  - Long Beach homes and buildings including Cerritos Ranch, 1885; undated (Box 24, Item 1744-1748)
  - Los Angeles area railways and electric railways, includes Santa Monica Railroad; L.A. and Independent; and San Pedro and Los Angeles Railroad facilities and trains; Pacific Electric Railroad facilities, 1873; undated (Box 24, Item 1749-1760)
  - Los Angeles County. Non-locational objects and unidentified locations, including "Rubbottoms bowie;" "Editorial Corps of the Weekly Comet;" Possible residences of Cameron Thom; Mayes family residence; First Ebell Club, undated (Box 24, Item 1761-1783)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified Los Angeles, undated (Box 25, Items 1783a-1783o)
  - Los Angeles County unidentified and miscellaneous includes street views, unidentified buildings and homes, engravings, 1878; undated (Box 26, Item 1784-1797)
  - Hansen surveys of various Los Angeles sites and Wilmington, 1864-1866; undated (Box 26, Item 1798-1825)
  - Hansen surveys, maps and notes; Various Los Angeles and San Gabriel properties, including Spadra and San Gabriel, 1853; 1855,; undated (Box 27, Item 1826-1837)
  - Ords Survey, 1849 (Box 27, Item 1838-1841a)
  - Lecouvreurs Grade drawings, 1873 (Box 27, Item 1842-1848)
  - Waldemar surveys, 1857 (Box 27, Item 1849-1850)
  - Miscellaneous maps, of Los Angeles and San Diego Bay, makers unknown, undated (Box 27, Item 1851-1853)
  - Field notes on various Los Angeles area properties, unknown creator, 1855 (Box 27, Item 1854-1861)
  - Assessment, title page through page 4, 1850 (Box 27, Item 1862-1864)